# Seth Greenbaum

Denver, CO ~ (410) 917-4427

sethmgreenbaum@gmail.com

Offering experience in molecular biology, food manufacturing, process automation, and IT, in both laboratory and industrial contexts, as well as a focus on the application of scientific methods and technology to both R&D and production.

#### **Education/Certification**

Bachelor of Arts in Biology: Oberlin College, Oberlin, OH Spring 2013

University of Denver Full-Stack Coding Bootcamp, Certificate Spring 2020

American Society of Plant Biologists, member since 2014

## Work Experience

Green Chef/Hello Fresh: Boulder, CO 2015 - current position -Process and Industrial Engineer, Automation and Engineering Services:

Provided scientific technical support for innovation and continuous improvement in the areas of organic grocery and e-commerce; designed testing programs for shipping technology and packaging; pursued cost savings through food processing, packaging and pack line automation; built analytical and reporting tools for monitoring production processes; determined guidelines for produce handling through shelf-life studies and microbiological tests;

Dept. of Biology, Oberlin College: Oberlin, OH, 2013-2014 -Research technician:

Managed Plant Molecular Biology Laboratory of Dr. Marta Laskowski, conducted and presented research on organ development and hormone-gene interactions n in *Arabidopsis thaliana*, assisted undergraduate research

Student Academic Services, Oberlin College:, Oberlin, OH, 2012-2013 -Biology Tutor

Campus Dining Services, Oberlin College: Oberlin, OH, 2010-2013 -Food Service Worker:

<u>Dept. of Chemistry, Oberlin College: Oberlin, OH 2011-2012</u> -Chemistry Stockroom Assistant:

<u>Yaffa Catering:</u>, <u>Baltimore</u>, <u>MD 2008-2009</u> -Kitchen and Commissary Worker:

Wilmer Eye Institute: Johns Hopkins University Baltimore, MD 2008 -Summer IT Assistant:

#### **Volunteer Experience**

Oberlin Student Cooperative Association, Oberlin, OH 2010-2011 -Dinner Head Cook:

<u>Wilmer Eye Institute Johns Hopkins University, Baltimore MD 2012</u> -Research Intern: in the Laboratory of Dr. Debasish Sinha and Dr. Malika Valapala, assisted in research on autophagy processes in a potential model for Macular Degeneration

<u>Wilmer Eye Institute Johns Hopkins University, Baltimore, MD 2006, 2007</u> -Research Intern: In the Laboratory of Dr, Elia Duh, learned molecular biology techniques and aided research

#### **Technical Skills**

Microsoft Office, Google Suite, Google Apps Script, HTML, CSS, Python, JavaScript, R, SPSS, MATLAB, MaxMSP, Adobe Suite

### **Publications and Presentations**

Valapala M, Wilson C, Hose S, Bhutto IA, Grebe R, Dong A, Greenbaum S, Gu L, Sengupta S, Cano M, et al. Lysosomal- mediated waste clearance in retinal pigment epithelial cells is regulated by CRYBA1/β A3/A1-crystallin via V-ATPase- MTORC1 signaling. Autophagy 2014; 10:85 - 101; PMID: 24468901;

Greenbaum S, Du Y, Laskowski M, "COI1 dependent and COI1 independent mechanisms of Lateral Root Positioning". Poster presented at American Society of Plant Biologists Midwest Section Meeting 2014 March 22-23; Columbus, Ohio